<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>MWFrost.com</title>
 <link href="http://mwfrost.github.io/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://mwfrost.github.io"/>
 <updated>2015-11-02T08:38:09-08:00</updated>
 <id>http://mwfrost.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Matt Frost</name>
   <email>mwfrost@fastmail.fm</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Coal Retirement Plan</title>
   <link href="http://mwfrost.github.io/coal_retirement_plan"/>
   <updated>2015-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://mwfrost.github.io/coal_retirement_plan</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A very rough draft of an idea I’ve been discussing on twitter, posted here for reference and continued conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;table&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;TL/DR:&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;The U.S. government should modify the legal infrastructure for mineral resources such that the carbon in undeveloped fossil fuels can be purchased and reserved in perpetual easements.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a carbon mitigation skeptic. That is, I doubt the social and technological tools at our disposal can avert the next hundred years of likely anthropogenic climate change. Without a breakthrough in energy production, free CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; capture, or both, atmospheric concentrations of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; will remain high enough to continue to force global warming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the optimistic claims of the pro-mitigation establishment, as represented by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipcc.ch&quot; title=&quot;IPCC&quot;&gt;International Panel on Climate Change&lt;/a&gt;, the climate problem is, at the moment, an insoluble one. That is, we don’t yet know the means by which we will stabilize and reduce atmospheric CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2014-10-29/while-you-were-getting-worked-up-over-oil-prices-this-just-happened-to-solar&quot; title=&quot;While You Were Getting Worked Up Over Oil Prices, This Just Happened to Solar&quot;&gt;Solar power costs are falling faster&lt;/a&gt; than most observers have dared hope, but global demand for inexpensive energy, especially in the developing economies where coal is essential to continued growth, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iea.org/newsroomandevents/pressreleases/2014/december/global-coal-demand-to-reach-9-billion-tonnes-per-year-by-2019.html&quot; title=&quot;Global coal demand to reach 9 billion tonnes per year by 2019&quot;&gt;will continue to outpace&lt;/a&gt; our supply of non-fossil sources, which is why neither China nor India is likely to implement carbon constraints in the forseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coal&quot;&gt;Coal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coal is a popular villain in the climate change story, and for good reason. It’s the consumption of coal for power generation that loaded the atmosphere with carbon in the first place, coal emissions account for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/publications/freepublications/publication/CO2EmissionsFromFuelCombustionHighlights2014.pdf&quot; title=&quot;CO2 EMISSIONS FROM FUEL COMBUSTION Highlights (2014 Edition)&quot;&gt;over forty percent of global CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions,&lt;/a&gt; and the growth in coal-fired electric plants will continue for the near future. As long as coal remains cheap—as long as its price excludes the externalities of carbon pollution—utilities will continue to use it rather than gas or nuclear power for electric generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mainstream proposals make unreasonable assumptions about the likelihood of aligning global incentives or encouraging technological investment in renewable energy sources, and plans that attempt to reconcile carbon abatement with the inevitable continued use of coal are especially guilty of such unfounded optimism. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/coal/&quot; title=&quot;The Future of Coal: An Interdisciplinary MIT Study&quot;&gt;2007 interdisciplinary study published by MIT&lt;/a&gt;, for example, endorses carbon capture and storage (CCS) as the most promising way to reduce emissions from new coal-fired power plants overseas, and insists that any new plants be built with CCS. Even if the U.S. could, as the report recommends, encourage developing nations to test and implement CCS, this would only improve the emissions from newly constructed facilities, and the parasitic load of capture equipment would require more coal to be burned to produce each unit of output. Even this high-profile study from a flagship American institution advises little more than a program of wishful thinking with meager results. Reducing carbon by burning coal to power a device to strip CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; from coal-fired flue gas makes little sense to anyone without a direct interest in promoting such boondoggles (like this writer, a few years ago), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pennenergy.com/articles/pennenergy/2013/12/mission-possible-an-environmentalist-looks-at-coal-power-and-climate.html?cmpid=EnlWeeklyPowerJanuary32014&quot; title=&quot;A more optimistic look at CCS&quot;&gt;although at least one comitted climate activist disagrees.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;policy-solutions&quot;&gt;Policy Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ideal solution to anthropogenic climate change is a zero-carbon energy source cheaper than fossil fuels, and a means of using that energy to capture previously-emitted carbon from the atmosphere. In the absence of cheap zero-carbon energy, the developed economies have tried to price CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-related externalities into the market cost of coal, oil, and natural gas, in hopes that renewable or low-carbon alternatives would become less expensive in comparison. Because coal is more carbon-intensive than natural gas or petroleum, it is the fuel source most sensitive to the imposition of carbon-based penalties, and offers the greatest potential for single-source carbon reduction. None of the various attempts to reduce CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions, such as a carbon tax or a credit trading market, have been successful in the U.S., though, partly because they would establish sweeping new regulatory regimes, and therefore invite resistance from entire industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as my gift to America’s environmental policy entrepreneurs, here’s a proposal that focuses on the fuel source and sector with the greatest potential for incremental carbon abatement, could reduce emissions by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2012/07/120716214334.htm&quot; title=&quot;Replacing coal with natural gas would reduce global warming&quot;&gt;about 40 percent of the reduction that a full switch to low-carbon resources would accomplish&lt;/a&gt;, uses currently available technology, does not require unrealistic levels of international cooperation, does not create artificial markets in ephemeral government-enforced carbon credits, and can be financed with philanthropic funds or federal spending. It uses small-bore regulatory reform to leverage private support for carbon mitigation without the political backlash that coercive regulation invites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sequestration-without-extraction&quot;&gt;Sequestration Without Extraction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The U.S. government should modify the legal infrastructure for mineral resources such that the carbon in undeveloped fossil fuels can be purchased and reserved in perpetual easements. Private activists and even coal-competing energy developers could buy in-situ coal with the assurance that its carbon would never be released through combustion. The government could even use its own funds to establish an “undeveloped carbon reserve” as a carbon reduction strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strategically shrewd “investors” in unmined coal, motivated by the desire to prevent its mining and prop up its price, would start buying up tracts with the most economically viable reserves and continue down the supply curve, ideally until the spot price for coal meets that of natural gas. This would encourage the fuel-switching that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/2012/07/14/156784701/miners-weather-the-slow-burn-of-coals-demise&quot; title=&quot;NPR: Miners Weather the Slow Burn of Coal&#39;s Demise&quot;&gt;is already underway&lt;/a&gt; in the U.S., thanks to the shale gas boom and recent regulations restricting coal. Additional regulations, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.regulations.gov/#!docketDetail;D=EPA-HQ-RCRA-2009-0640&quot; title=&quot;Regulation of coal waste&quot;&gt;treating power plant ash as a hazardous waste&lt;/a&gt;, or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.epa.gov/mats/actions.html&quot; title=&quot;Mercury Rule&quot;&gt;monitoring and control of mercury emissions&lt;/a&gt;, are likely to nudge the relative price of coal higher still. Since natural gas has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.cfm?id=7890&quot; title=&quot;Today in Energy&quot;&gt;about half the carbon content of coal per unit of energy&lt;/a&gt;, the switch to gas reduces the country’s carbon intensity, allowing us to generate the same amount of economic output for fewer tons of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. There’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://rhg.com/notes/coal-claws-back&quot; title=&quot;Rhodium Group » Coal Claws Back&quot;&gt;nothing innately irreversible&lt;/a&gt; about this; natural gas prices could rebound and coal could regin some of its lost market share, but a shock to coal prices caused by the sudden arrival of a new market, could lock in this domestic shift, perhaps permanently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purchased reserves would be placed off-limits to extraction in perpetuity (but could perhaps remain available for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/climate/2008/0803/full/climate.2008.18.html&quot; title=&quot;Underground Coal Gasification&quot;&gt;underground gasification&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:36&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:36&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Since the U.S. contains &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldcoal.org/bin/pdf/original_pdf_file/coal_matters_2_-_global_availability_of_coal(16_05_2012).pdf&quot; title=&quot;Global Availability of Coal&quot;&gt;the largest share of the world’s coal reserves&lt;/a&gt;, and exported &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eia.gov/coal/production/quarterly/pdf/t7p01p1.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Coal production stats from the EIA&quot;&gt;126 million tons in 2012&lt;/a&gt;, domestic market shifts could cause natural gas and renewable energy sources to become more competitive with coal on a global basis without the need for internationally binding agreements. Additionally, because coal deposits are so widely distributed, this policy is one that could be reproduced and extended by other coal-producing nations where policy elites endorse carbon mitigation, such as Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;simple-and-incremental&quot;&gt;Simple and Incremental&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An energy-efficient system minimizes the number of state changes through which energy must pass. An elegant policy solution to atmospheric CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; accumulation will similarly operate in as direct a manner as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, a climate activist who hopes to convert money into carbon mitgation can choose from among several different bank shots, such as political engagement, purchasing carbon offsets, or investing in alternative energy. In all these approaches, uncertainty and complexity dilute the carbon-reducing value of each dollar spent. Buying undeveloped fossil fuel and preventing it from ever being combusted results in both the direct benefit of sequestering the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;sub&amp;gt; and the secondary effect of nudging prices upward by reducing coal available to other buyers. Private citizens and philanthropists could use their own funds to lock up coal reserves and corner the market, rather than &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/10/19/magazine/how-billionaire-oligarchs-are-becoming-their-own-political-parties.html?_r=0&quot; title=&quot;How Billionaire Oligarchs are Becoming Their Own Political Parties&quot;&gt;lavishing money on political operatives and consultants&lt;/a&gt; and launching advocacy projects of dubious impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A national or international cap-and-trade system appeals to those who enjoy sweeping, high-stakes political challenges, but it suffers from being an all-or-nothing commitment. To crudely stylize the democratic process, getting 49% of the votes means getting zero percent of the results. The money spent on developing and selling a high-profile policy solution might not be totally wasted, since institution-building can be a gradual process, but resources devoted to lobbying for cap-and-trade have yet to directly prevent any CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions. By making one rather esoteric adjustment to U.S. properry law, my proposal allows each marginal dollar spent to have some small impact toward increasing the cost of burning coal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-role-of-the-blm&quot;&gt;The role of the BLM&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blm.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;A dragline working in the Powder River Basin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A dragline working in the Powder River Basin: BLM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US federal government, through the Bureau of Land Management, is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sourcewatch.org/index.php?title=Coal_reserves#Ownership_of_U.S._coal_reserves&quot; title=&quot;Important caveat on Wikipedia: &amp;ldquo;Note: Figure for U.S. Government is based on a National Mining Association calculation based on federal ownership of about one-third of the United States&#39; coal reserves of 264 billion short tons.&amp;rdquo;&quot;&gt;country’s largest coal owner&lt;/a&gt;, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blm.gov/wo/st/en/prog/energy/coal_and_non-energy.print.html&quot;&gt;responsibility for 570 million acres of coal mineral estate&lt;/a&gt;. The BLM &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blm.gov/wo/st/en/prog/more/climatechange.html&quot;&gt;already pays lip service&lt;/a&gt; to a carbon mitigation mission. It’s even “exploring the potential to sequester carbon dioxide in geologic formations beneath public lands.” Treating sequestration reservoirs as a natural resource makes good sense. Given the availability of better energy sources, sequestering that carbon with financial and legal instruments &lt;em&gt;before excavating and burning it&lt;/em&gt; makes even more sense. Creative legislators and regulators could develop a follow-on to the Federal Coal Leasing Amendments Act of 1976 (FCLAA), which amended Section 2 of the Mineral Leasing Act of 1920, and turn “carbon easement” into a type of coal lease, and integrate it into the BLM’s competitive leasing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new market for BLM’s coal would arrive just in time, since the agency &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.desmogblog.com/2013/09/19/end-powder-river-basin-coal-leases-second-auction-two-months-fails-seal-mining-deal&quot;&gt;can’t seem to find any buyers&lt;/a&gt; at current prices. A single bid of $0.21 per ton for a tract of Powder River Basin coal was rejected in 2013, so that coal stayed in the ground for another year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comparability-with-alternate-carbon-abatement-methods&quot;&gt;Comparability with alternate carbon abatement methods&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s stop for a minute and look at that failed lease bid. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blm.gov/wy/st/en/info/news_room/2013/september/18-coalsaleresults.html&quot;&gt;bidders offered $35,070,331 for 167 million projected tons of coal&lt;/a&gt;. Using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eia.gov/coal/production/quarterly/co2_article/co2.html&quot;&gt;EIA’s conversion factor&lt;/a&gt; of 1,685.5 kg of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; per short ton of subbituminous coal, that works out to 281,478,500 metric tons of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. $35 million divided by 281.5 million works out to $0.124 per metric ton of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; abatement. Terrapass, meanwhile, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.terrapass.com/shop/busines-carbon-offsets/&quot;&gt;will happily take $13.12 of your money&lt;/a&gt; in exchange for offsetting a metric ton of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions. These costs are not, of course, directly comparable, since the government expects royalties on the mined coal as well as the lease price for the unmined acres, but the spread between the cost of in-situ coal and the cost of standard offset schemes (biogas digesters, etc.) is larger than I expected, and encouraging the BLM to forgo its royalty payments in exchange for carbon sequestration isn’t unimaginable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coalitions-for-and-against&quot;&gt;Coalitions, for and against&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying up prime coal reserves and rendering them off-limits to mining would cut the coal mining industry off at the knees. This is a feature of any meaningful carbon abatement plan, though, since CCS is still both unproven and expensive. A tough regulatory environment is already preparing the battlefield by whittling away at the domestic market, so my proposed buyout may look, in comparison, like a more graceful exit for coal owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural gas producers would stand to gain, as would the holders of those coal reserves left on the open market, at least in the near term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;obstacles-and-complications&quot;&gt;Obstacles and Complications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasing the market price of coal increases the economically recoverable reserve base. Technological progress that lowers the cost of mining could undercut the government-bid price, and mining companies could leapfrog over the off-market reserves to previously less accessible deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gas prices are volatile, and could become higher than coal if the unconventional gas boom dies out or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/christopherhelman/2014/04/24/solar-is-booming-but-will-never-replace-coal/&quot; title=&quot;Solar is Booming but Will Never Replace Coal&quot;&gt;supply is diverted away from generation for export purposes&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pennenergy.com/articles/pennenergy/2013/12/mission-possible-an-environmentalist-looks-at-coal-power-and-climate.html?cmpid=EnlWeeklyPowerJanuary32014&quot; title=&quot;Armond Cohen on clean coal tech&quot;&gt;Coal will remain popular overseas&lt;/a&gt;, especially in Asia, even if U.S. buyers tweak the price upwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.co2offsetresearch.org/consumer/Additionality.html&quot;&gt;Additionality&lt;/a&gt; can be a problem: if the coal was never going to be mined, there has been no incremental CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; abatement. Allowing easement buyers to help the coal market clear, however, would still reduce perceived supply and support prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Suggest other problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;macroeconomic-implications&quot;&gt;Macroeconomic Implications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What would be the macro implications?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ballpark-numbers&quot;&gt;Ballpark Numbers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much money would this take? How much would it move prices?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have taken some well-deserved grief on twitter for the absence of numbers in this proposal. As I explained, the necessary values for a back-of-the-envelope guess aren’t readily available, but I owe the reader some ballpark figures. Here are some tentative steps toward providing the variables that would make up an economic model of my plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-situ-coal-prices&quot;&gt;In-Situ Coal Prices&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost of unmined coal isn’t published the way different index prices are, but the per-ton royalty rate paid by a mining company to the mineral owner is a good proxy. The royalty reflects the value of the coal before any downstream services like extraction or transportation have been performed. To compensate a mineral holder for rendering his or her resources unmineable, the retirement price of the coal would have to match or exceed the present value of the expected royalty income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blm.gov/wo/st/en/prog/energy/coal_and_non-energy.print.html&quot;&gt;BLM charges 12% per ton of surface coal and 8% per ton of underground coal&lt;/a&gt;. A ton of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eia.gov/coal/news_markets/&quot;&gt;Powder River Basin coal that sells for $12&lt;/a&gt; will earn the federal government a $1.44 royalty payment. Using the EIA’s conversion factor again, that $1.44 could have sequestered 1.7 metric tonnes of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. Terrapass, remember, charges &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.terrapass.com/shop/busines-carbon-offsets/&quot;&gt;$13.12 per tonne&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of October 2014, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-22/coal-miners-fired-in-appalachia-getting-hired-in-wyoming.html&quot; title=&quot;Coal Miners Fired in Appalachia Getting Hired in Wyoming&quot;&gt;PRB coal cost Alpha Natural Resources around $11/ton to mine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:36&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Reader Oliver Tickell &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theecologist.org/News/news_analysis/2402220/coal_gas_company_warns_stop_campaigning_or_we_will_sue.html&quot; title=&quot;Coal gas company warns - stop campaigning or we will sue&quot;&gt;suggests that underground gasification is to be avoided&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:36&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>An Old Manuscript</title>
   <link href="http://mwfrost.github.io/an-old-manuscript"/>
   <updated>2012-11-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://mwfrost.github.io/an-old-manuscript</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my own translation of a Kafka story I couldn’t find in English online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Franz Kafka&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s as if something had been neglected in the defense of our fatherland. So far, we haven’t cared for it, and were pursuing our work; but the events of the last times made us concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Es ist, als wäre viel vernachlässigt worden in der Verteidigung unseres Vaterlandes. Wir haben uns bisher nicht darum gekümmert und sind unserer Arbeit nachgegangen; die Ereignisse der letzten Zeit machen uns aber Sorgen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a cobbler’s shop on the square in front of the imperial palace. I’ve scarcely opened my shop in the dawn darkness and I already see the entrances to the incoming streets occupied by armed men. It’s not our soldiers, but rather nomads from the north. It’s incomprehensible to me that the’ve already penetrated to the capital, which is so far from the border. Anyway, there they are; it seems like more arrive every morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ich habe eine Schusterwerkstatt auf dem Platz vor dem kaiserlichen Palast. Kaum öffne ich in der Morgendämmerung meinen Laden, sehe ich schon die Eingänge aller hier einlaufenden Gassen von Bewaffneten besetzt. Es sind aber nicht unsere Soldaten, sondern offenbar Nomaden aus dem Norden. Auf eine mir unbegreifliche Weise sind sie bis in die Hauptstadt gedrungen, die doch sehr weit von der Grenze entfernt ist. Jedenfalls sind sie also da; es scheint, daß jeden Morgen mehr werden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their true nature kept them under open skies, since they loathed homes. They busied themselves with sharpening swords, honing arrows, exercising horses. Of this quiet square that’s always kept so fussily clean, they’ve made a real sty. We try sometimes to rush out of our shops and and at least haul off the worst of the filth, but it happens ever more seldom, because the effort is futile and, what’s more, puts us in danger of being trampled by the wild horses or lashed by the whips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ihrer Natur entsprechend lagern sie unter freiem Himmel, denn Wohnhäuser verabscheuen sie. Sie beschäftigen sich mit dem Schärfen der Schwerter, dem Zuspitzen der Pfeile, mit Übungen zu Pferde. Aus diesem stillen, immer ängstlich rein gehaltenen Platz haben sie einen wahren Stall gemacht. Wir versuchen zwar manchmal aus unseren Geschäften hervorzulaufen und wenigstens den ärgsten Unrat wegzuschaffen, aber es geschieht immer seltener, denn die Anstrengung ist nutzlos und bringt uns überdies in die Gefahr, unter die wilden Pferde zu kommen oder von den Peitschen verletzt zu werden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t speak with the nomads. They don’t know our language, and they barely have one of their own. Among themselves they converse almost like jackdaws. Again and again you hear these screeches of jackdaws. Our way of life, our events are as baffling to them as they are indifferent. For this reason they also showed themselves reluctant to use any sign language. You might dislocate your jaw and pull your hands out of joint: they haven’t understood you and they never will. Often they make grimacing faces, then the whites of their eyes appear and foam pours from their mouths. They don’t really want to frighten you or say anything; they just do it because it is their way. What they need, they take. You can’t say that they apply violence. Before their entrance, you step aside and leave them alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sprechen kann man mit den Nomaden nicht. Unsere Sprache kennen sie nicht, ja sie haben kaum eine eigene. Unter einander verständigen sie sich ähnlich wie Dohlen. Immer wieder hört man diesen Schrei der Dohlen. Unsere Lebensweise, unsere Einrichtungen sind ihnen ebenso unbegreiflich wie gleichgültig. Infolgedessen zeigen sie sich auch gegen jede Zeichensprache ablehnend. Du magst dir die Kiefer verrenken und die Hände aus den Gelenken winden, sie haben dich doch nicht verstanden und werden dich nie verstehen. Oft machen sie Grimassen; dann dreht sich das Weiß ihrer Augen und Schaum schwillt aus ihrem Munde, doch wollen sie damit weder etwas sagen noch auch erschrecken; sie tun es, weil es so ihre Art ist. Was sie brauchen, nehmen sie. Man kann nicht sagen, daß sie Gewalt anwenden. Vor ihrem Zugriff tritt man beiseite und überläßt ihnen alles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’ve also taken some good pieces of my inventory. I can’t complain about it, though, when I see, for example, what’s happened to the butcher. No sooner does he get his wares than they’re snatched away and devoured by the nomads. Their horses eat meat, too; oten a rider lies next to his horse, and both gnaw on the same piece of flesh, one at each end. The butcher is anxious, and doesn’t dare stop delivery of his meat. We understand, though, and we all chip in to support him. If the nomads don’t get meat, who knows what will occur to them to do? Who knows, though, what will occur to them to do, even if they get meat daily?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Auch von meinen Vorräten haben sie manches gute Stück genommen. Ich kann aber darüber nicht klagen, wenn ich zum Beispiel zusehe, wie es dem Fleischer gegenüber geht. Kaum bringt er seine Waren ein, ist ihm schon alles entrissen und wird von den Nomaden verschlungen. Auch ihre Pferde fressen Fleisch; oft liegt ein Reiter neben seinem Pferd und beide nähren sich vom gleichen Fleischstück, jeder an einem Ende. Der Fleischhauer ist ängstlich und wagt es nicht, mit den Fleischlieferungen aufzuhören. Wir verstehen das aber, schießen Geld zusammen und unterstützen ihn. Bekämen die Nomaden kein Fleisch, wer weiß, was ihnen zu tun einfiele; wer weiß allerdings, was ihnen einfallen wird, selbst wenn sie täglich Fleisch bekommen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the butcher thought he could at least save himself the trouble of slaughtering, and brought a living ox one morning. He won’t do &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; again. I lay for a good hour flat on the floot in the very back of my shop with all my clothes, covers, and upholstery piled over me just to keep from hearing the bellowing of the ox as the nomads sprang on it from all sides and with their teeth tore pieces out of its warm flesh. It was silent for a long time before I dared to go outside; like drunks around a wine cask, they lay exhausted around the remains of the ox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Letzthin dachte der Fleischer, er könne sich wenigstens die Mühe des Schlachtens sparen, und brachte am Morgen einen lebendigen Ochsen. Das darf er nicht mehr wiederholen. Ich lag wohl eine Stunde ganz hinten in meiner Werkstatt platt auf dem Boden und alle meine Kleider, Decken und Polster hatte ich über mir aufgehäuft, nur um das Gebrüll des Ochsen nicht zu hören, den von allen Seiten die Nomaden ansprangen, um mit den Zähnen Stücke aus seinem warmen Fleisch zu reißen. Schon lange war es still, ehe ich mich auszugehen getraute; wie Trinker um ein Weinfaß lagen sie müde um die Reste des Ochsen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right then I thought I’d seen the emperor himself in a window of the palace; otherwise he never comes out into these shops, he only stays in the inner garden; but this time he stood there, or so it seemed to me, at his window and looked with lowered head at the tribulations in front of his castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Gerade damals glaubte ich den Kaiser selbst in einem Fenster des Palastes gesehen zu haben; niemals sonst kommt er in diese äußeren Gemächer, immer nur lebt er in dem innersten Garten; diesmal aber stand er, so schien es mir wenigstens, an einem der Fenster und blickte mit gesenktem Kopf auf das Treiben vor seinem Schloß.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What will become of it all?” we ask. “How long will we endure these burdens and torments?” The imperial palace attracted the nomads, but it didn’t understand how to drive them off. The tower remained locked; the imperial guard, which used to march splendidly in and out, kept itself behind shuttered windows. To us craftsmen and merchants is entrusted the protection of the fatherland; but we aren’t up to such a task, nor have we ever boasted to be. It is a misunderstanding, and we will perish because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;»Wie wird es werden?« fragen wir uns alle. »Wie lange werden wir diese Last und Qual ertragen? Der kaiserliche Palast hat die Nomaden angelockt, versteht es aber nicht, sie wieder zu vertreiben. Das Tor bleibt verschlossen; die Wache, früher immer festlich ein- und ausmarschierend, hält sich hinter vergitterten Fenstern. Uns Handwerkern und Geschäftsleuten ist die Rettung des Vaterlandes anvertraut; wir sind aber einer solchen Aufgabe nicht gewachsen; haben uns doch auch nie gerühmt, dessen fähig zu sein. Ein Mißverständnis ist es, und wir gehen daran zugrunde.«&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>